<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!--
  * Copyright (c) 2011-2015, BULL SAS, NovaForge Version 3 and above.
  *
  * This file is free software: you may redistribute and/or modify it under
  * the terms of the GNU Affero General Public License as published by the
  * Free Software Foundation, version 3 of the License.
  *
  * This file is distributed in the hope that it will be useful,
  * but WITHOUT ANY WARRANTY; without even the implied warranty
  * of MERCHANTABILITY or FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE.
  * See the GNU Affero General Public License for more details.
  * You should have received a copy of the GNU Affero General Public License
  * along with this program. If not, see http://www.gnu.org/licenses.
  *
  * Additional permission under GNU AGPL version 3 (AGPL-3.0) section 7.
  *
  * If you modify this Program, or any covered work, by linking or combining
  * it with libraries listed in COPYRIGHT file at the top-level directory of
  * this distribution (or a modified version of that libraries), containing parts
  * covered by the terms of licenses cited in the COPYRIGHT file, the licensors
  * of this Program grant you additional permission to convey the resulting work.
  -->

<chapter version="5.0" xml:lang="en" xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook"
		>
	<title>Introduction</title>

	<section>
		<title>This document</title>

		<para>NovaForgeTM is a secured collaborative platform which offers
			features to manage projects and simplify software development. This
			document is divided into several chapters. In the first chapters you
			will learn the basic actions such as creating an account, navigating
			through the forge and creating and managing a project. The remaining
			chapters describe each feature included in NovaForgeTM.</para>
	</section>

	<section>
		<title>New features of Version 3</title>

		<para>NovaForgeTM Version 3 is based on a completely new architecture
			according to SOA (Service Oriented Architecture) patterns. The forge
			is in fact subdivided into functional services (technical event
			management, document management, configuration management,
			requirement management, etc.). Each functional service is then
			implemented by one or more technical solutions (for example, Mantis
			is a technical solution to the &quot;technical event management&quot;
			functional service). All these services can be accessed from a
			secured collaborative portal which manages user rights to the various
			products, user identification and the links between the tools.</para>

		<para>NovaForge v3 includes some 15 tools:</para>

		<itemizedlist>
			<listitem>
				<para>Open Source leader tools: Mantis, Jenkins, Alfresco, SVN,
					Testlink, Sonar, Nexus, LimeSurvey, DokuWiki, PhpBB, Sympa, etc.
				</para>
			</listitem>

			<listitem>
				<para>NovaForge specific tools used to manage requirement tracking,
					manage deliveries, etc.</para>
			</listitem>
		</itemizedlist>

		<para>One of the basic principles of NovaForge v3 is the plugin
			concept: each component is included as a plugin. This principle makes
			NovaForge extremely flexible, both in terms of use and installation.
			It is in fact relatively easy to add components. The architecture
			therefore simplifies integration of a new functional service or a new
			technical component. Concerning usability, the notion of plugin
			allows several instances of the same component to be instantiated in
			a project (e.g. several Mantis for the same project: one external and
			one internal). In addition, communication can be defined between the
			plugins, for example to create a bug directly from the test tool or
			from the delivery tool, retrieve sources from the SVN, documents from
			documentary management and bugs from the bug tracker.</para>

		<para>Amongst the numerous other new features of NovaForge v3, the
			remaining documentation describes the notion of project template,
			reference project, delivery management module, requirement tracking
			module, etc.</para>
	</section>
</chapter>
